Hello, English learners,
and welcome to another
lesson with English
Pod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're bringing
you a great Christmas lesson.
That's right, we've got a lot of Christmas
vocabulary in today's lesson for you.
Yeah, it's almost Christmas time, so everyone
is getting into the spirit, especially
here at English Pod, so we're going
to teach you a little bit more about this.
Speaking of the spirit, I think it's time
for us to look at our vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
So in this part of
our show, we'll look at
some key language in
the dialogue that you'll
need to know to
understand the dialogue.
And actually today we
only have one word, egg
nog, egg nog, egg nog,
e-g-g-n-o-g, egg nog.
So egg nog is a really
popular Christmas drink.
It's a traditional Christmas drink.
Right.
What is it made of?
Eggs, cream, sugar, and usually rum.
Rum.
Oh, so it has alcohol.
Yeah, normally.
It has alcohol.
Okay.
All right.
That's interesting.
There's actually a drink
very similar to this in Chile.
Really?
Yep.
They call it monkey tail.
So in Spanish, that
would be... Go la de mono.
Very nice.
Yeah, so it's actually really, really good.
Man, it's really similar to egg nog.
Okay.
Well, with that in mind, let's take a
listen to our dialogue for the first time.
I hate working on Christmas Eve.
Whoa!
Get a load of this guy.
Come in, Central.
I think we got ourselves a situation here.
I've been drinking tonight, sir.
I had one or two glasses
of egg nog, but nothing else.
Step out of the vehicle, please.
Sir, what do you have in the back?
You have to feel Christmas gifts.
Don't take that tone with me.
Do you have an invoice for these items?
No.
I make these in my
workshop in the North Pole.
You are under arrest, sir.
You have the right to remain silent.
You better not power, you better not cry.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you can't afford one, the
state will appoint one for you.
Do you understand these rights
that have just been read to you?
You can't take me to jail.
What about my sleigh?
It's Christmas Eve.
I have presents to deliver.
Rudolph, Prince or dancer, you'd help.
Well, I did not see that one coming.
That was interesting.
Santa Claus is being taken to jail.
What's going to happen next, Marco?
I don't know.
Let's talk about that in a little while.
Let's take a look at some
language from this dialogue.
Language takeaway.
So the first word that we have on
our language takeaway today is vehicle.
Vehicle.
So this is a vehicle.
And this is a vehicle.
So all of those are vehicles.
Now, I thought that a
vehicle was a car specifically.
No, any machine that carries people
from one place to another is a vehicle.
Great.
All right.
Let's take a look now at our second word.
Attorney, attorney, attorney.
So what is an attorney?
A lawyer.
Well, that's simple enough.
Yeah, a lawyer.
Let's move to our third word,
which is a point, a point, a point.
So a point means choose.
OK.
So the president of a country
might appoint his chief of staff, right?
Or I can appoint my attorney.
True.
So can you appoint a thing?
Can I appoint my coffee cup?
No, no.
You only use it for people.
You choose someone.
OK, I'll appoint something.
So I appoint someone.
Exactly.
All right.
Let's move to our final word.
Slay.
So Erica, you're from Canada.
You can tell us about slays.
All right.
A slay is a vehicle that is pulled by
a horse and travels over snow or ice.
OK.
So like Santa drives a slay.
He drives a slay.
So do you drive a slay or ride a slay?
Good question.
Well, the song says you
ride in a one horse open slay.
Right.
OK.
Well, you know what?
I think it's time for
us to look at some
interesting phrases that
we found in this dialogue.
So let's look at putting it together.
Putting it together.
Today I'm putting it together.
We have two great phrases for you.
And let's take a look at the first one.
Step out.
So step out means to go out of
a place for a short period of time.
Right.
So in our dialogue, for example, the police
officer said step out of the vehicle.
Get out of your vehicle.
You can also say step out of the office.
You can say I just
stepped out of the shower.
Right.
Now we can also say step in.
It's the opposite.
The opposite, right?
I can ask Marco, step into
my office for a moment.
Uh oh.
OK.
So that's step out and step in.
Great phrases.
Let's take a look at our final phrase.
Get a load of.
So when I say get a load of
something, I mean, look at, right?
Right, look at this guy.
Get a load of this guy.
Yeah, that's what we heard in the dialogue.
Now you can use this phrase
in a number of different ways.
And we have some examples for you.
Example one.
Get a load of this.
A war has started in Antarctica.
Example two.
Get a load of the house.
It's so big.
Example three.
Get a load of him.
He's wearing a pink suit.
OK.
I think we've covered a
lot of interesting words
and phrases, so we are ready to
listen to our dialogue a second time.
But this time it's
going to be a little bit
slower so we can pick
up all these great words.
I hate working on Christmas Eve.
Whoa.
Get a load of this guy.
Come in central.
I think we got ourselves a situation here.
License and registration, please.
Have you been drinking tonight, sir?
I had one or two glasses
of Vignog, but nothing else.
Step out of the vehicle, please.
Sir, what do you have in the back?
Just a few Christmas gifts.
Tis the season, after all.
Don't take that tone with me.
Do you have an invoice for these items?
Um, no.
I make these in my
workshop in the North Pole.
You are under arrest, sir.
You have the right to remain silent.
You better not pout.
You better not cry.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford one, the
state will appoint one for you.
Do you understand all these rights
that have just been read to you?
You can't take me to jail.
What about my sleigh?
It's Christmas Eve.
I have presents to deliver.
Rudolph, prancer, dancer, get help.
OK, so we noticed some
really great words and phrases.
And with this, now we can
start with some fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Today on Fluency Builder,
we have two great phrases
that you can use to sound a little
bit more natural when you speak.
That's right.
Our first phrase you can use, if you
want to say, don't speak to me like that.
Don't take that tone with me.
So you often hear this phrase coming
out of the mouth of a mother or a father.
Yeah, when their children
are maybe talking back.
Yeah.
Don't take that tone with me, young man.
I used to get that a lot.
Really?
I'm sorry about that.
OK, our second phrase, we
use it when we have a problem.
The phrase we heard in the dialogue was,
I think we've got
ourselves the situation here.
Let's listen to another example.
Houston, we've got
ourselves a situation here.
Sometimes I use this phrase when I
want to tell my boss that I have a problem.
I might say, boss, I've
got a bit of a situation.
Can you help me with it?
OK.
Yeah, I have a little bit of a problem.
Yeah, useful phrase, that's right.
Really useful phrases, great stuff.
So now we can listen to
our dialogue a final time.
And this time, we can
understand everything that's in it.
I hate working on Christmas Eve.
Whoa, get a load of this guy.
Come in, Central.
I think we got ourselves a situation here.
[INAUDIBLE]
Licensing registration, please.
Have you been drinking tonight, sir?
I had one or two glasses of
a high dog, but nothing else.
Step out of the vehicle, please.
Sir, what do you have in the back?
Just a few Christmas gifts.
Here's the season after all.
Don't take that tone with me.
Do you have an invoice for these items?
Oh, no, I make these in my
workshop in the North Pole.
You are under arrest, sir.
You have the rights remain silent.
You better not power, you better not cry.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you can't afford one, the
state will the point one for you.
Do you understand these rights
that have just been read to you?
You can't take me to
jail or to buy my sleigh.
It's Christmas Eve.
I have presents to deliver.
Rudolph, France, or dancer, you'd help.
So when the police officer was arresting
Santa Claus, he said something
a little bit strange, hey?
Yeah, he said, you better
not pout, you better not cry.
Now, are those part of the normal
rights that a police officer reads?
No, no.
They're not part of the
normal rights, but it's actually
from a Christmas song, so let's
listen to how it goes in the song.
I'm pretty happy we had a song to
play there instead of us having the sing.
But that's great
because if the children
cry or if they are not good kids, then
Santa Claus will not give them presents.
Uh-oh.
So that's why.
Okay, listeners, I hope
that you're not pouting.
I hope you're not crying, but it's time for
us to go, so be sure to go to our website
at EnglishPod.com and be
sure to leave all your questions
and comments and maybe
some of your Christmas stories.
All right, thanks for listening,
and until next time, bye-bye.